Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Records on Microfilm 5976 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- International Executive Board 1956-1964 (Reel 17)
  - 0425. Executive Board Correspondence (1958). 76 pages., 13 (Reel 17)
    Major Topics: Arrangements for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meetings; plans for investment of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters funds; plans for changing methods of handling Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters auditing; voter registration drive; opposition to "right to work" law movement.
  - 0501.Addresses [of] International Executive Board Members (1958). 6 pages., 14 (Reel 17)
  - 0507. International Executive Board Minutes (May 4-6, 1959). 19 pages., 15 (Reel 17)
  - 0526. International Executive Board Meeting (May 4-6, 1959). 26 pages., 16 (Reel 17)
    Major Topics: Agenda for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; report of the Finance Committee.
  - 0552. International Executive Board Minutes (Pre- and Post-Convention, September 1959). 15 pages., 17 (Reel 17)
    Major Topic: Minutes of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois.
  - 0567. International Executive Board Meeting (Pre-Convention, September 11-13, 1959). 74 pages., 18 (Reel 17)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters statement of receipts and expenditures; agenda for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; revision of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters constitution; report on Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board; recommendation to raise dues.
  - 0641. International Executive Board Correspondence (1959). 56 pages., 19 (Reel 17)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters contribution for Committee on Political Education; report on interest rates on government bonds; arrangements for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; dues collection; revision of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters constitution; financial problems of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters Los Angeles Division.
  - 0697. International Executive Board Minutes (May 31-June 2, 1960). 14 pages., 20 (Reel 17)
  - 0711. International Executive Board Meeting (May 31-June 2, 1960). 62 pages., 21 (Reel 17)
    Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters finances; arrangements for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; salaries of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters employees; agenda for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; reduction of per capita tax and assessment to the American Federation of Labor- Congress of Industrial Organizations; assets and liabilities of the International Association of Railway Employees; report of the Finance Committee.
  - 0773. International Executive Board Minutes (March 27-29, 1961). 54 pages., 22 (Reel 17)
    Major Topic: Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois.
  - 0790. International Executive Board Meeting (March 27, 1961). 54 pages., 23 (Reel 17)
    Major Topics: Complaint by dining car union regarding Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters raids on their employees; arrangements for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; agenda of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; report of the Finance Committee.
  - 0844. International Executive Board Minutes (December 1-2, 1961). 12 pages., 24 (Reel 17)
  - 0856. International Executive Board Meeting (December 4, 1961). 34 pages., 25 (Reel 17)
    Major Topics: Arrangements for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting and convention; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations group accident and disablement insurance plan; agenda for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters statement of receipts and disbursements.
  - 0890. International Executive Board (Reduction of Hours-February 16, 1962). 11 pages., 26 (Reel 17)
    Major Topics: Agenda and minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters plans for reduction of basic monthly hours.
  - 0901. Meeting of International Officers (Reduction of Hours - May 10, 1962). 2 pages., 27 (Reel 17)
    Major Topic: Agenda of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois.
  - 0903. International Executive Board Minutes (September 7, 1962). 13 pages., 28 (Reel 17)
    Major Topic: Minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Montreal, Canada.
  - 0916. International Executive Board minutes (June 3-4, 1963). 13 pages., 29 (Reel 17)
  - 0929. International Executive Board Meeting (May 31-June 4, 1963). 10 pages., 30 (Reel 17)
    Major Topics: Agenda for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; proposal for revision of proration procedure.
  - 0939. International Executive Board - General Correspondence (1963). 24 pages., 31 (Reel 17)
    Major Topics: Death of Ashley L. Totten; appointment of William H. Bowe as Acting International Secretary-Treasurer; readjustment of salaries for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters officials; arrangements and agenda for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters proposals for shorter work month, pay increase, and job stabilization program.
  - 0963. International Executive Board Minutes (January 7-9, 1964). 13 pages., 32 (Reel 17)
    Major Topics: Special assessment for building Brotherhood Fund; minutes of Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting held in Chicago, Illinois.
  - 0976. International Executive Board (1964). 25 pages., 33 (Reel 17)
    Major Topics: Proposed Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters sponsorship of a middle-class housing development; agenda for Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters International Executive Board meeting.
- Fair Employment Practices Commission Files 1941-1942 (Reel 18)
  - 0001. Fair Employment Practices Commission (June-September, 1941). 285 pages., 1 (Reel 18)
    Major Topics: Executive order reaffirming the policy of full participation in the defense program by all persons, regardless of race, creed, color, or national origin; Milton Webster's appointment as member of the Fair Employment Practices Commission; plans for integration of Negroes into national defense jobs; creation of the Labor Supply Branch of the Office of Production Management's Labor Division; complaints regarding discrimination in national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; government procurement policy; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; antidiscrimination clause in defense contracts.
  - 0286. Fair Employment Practices Commission (October-December 1941). 168 pages., 2 (Reel 18)
    Major Topics: Complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; antidiscrimination clause in defense contracts; Twin Cities Conference on the Training and Employment of Negroes for National Defense Industries; problems of Negro veterans; National Defense Mediation Board activities; labor disputes affecting war production; exclusion of Negroes from service in the United States Navy.
  - 0454. Fair Employment Practices Commission (1941). 77 pages., 3 (Reel 18)
    Major Topics: Efforts of Negro women to obtain jobs in industry; notes of defense work available for Negroes; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program; antidiscrimination clause in defense contracts; business training for defense; Fair Employment Practices Commission pamphlet on minorities in defense industries; schedule of bids received from the army and navy.
  - 0531. Fair Employment Practices Commission (January-February 15, 1942). 129 pages., 4 (Reel 18)
    Major Topics: Complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; labor's assistance of national war effort; efforts to increase number of defense workers; war labor disputes; establishment of the War Production Board and the National War Labor Board; resignation of Mark Ethridge as Fair Employment Practices Commission chairman; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meeting.
- Fair Employment Practices Commission Files 1942 (Reel 19)
  - 0001. Fair Employment Practices Commission (February 16-17, 1942). 614 pages., 1 (Reel 19)
    Major Topics: Negro employment and training; March on Washington Committee; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission hearings in the New York metropolitan area.
  - 0615. Fair Employment Practices Commission (February 18-March 1942). 109 pages., 2 (Reel 19)
    Major Topics: Summary of compliance with Fair Employment Practices Commission findings by firms in the Chicago area; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; proposed elimination of questions relating to race on government employment applications; appointment and tenure of Fair Employment Practices Commission members; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; preliminary report on defense training.
  - 0724. Fair Employment Practices Commission (April 1942). 262 pages., 3 (Reel 19)
    Major Topics: Complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; report on the Negroes in the defense industries; labor market problems; Negro employment and training; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission hearings; United States government policy and instructions to ensure full utilization of labor supply.
- Fair Employment Practices Commission Files 1942 (Reel 20)
  - 0001. Fair Employment Practices Commission (May-June 15, 1942). 168 pages., 1 (Reel 20)
    Major Topics: Complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; elimination of practice of introducing discriminatory specifications into employer orders; United states government policy and instructions to ensure full utilization of labor supply; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; Fair Employment Practices Commission hearings on Negro discrimination in the South; memorandum to Fair Employment Practices Commission submitted by representatives of the Southern Negro Youth Congress; Fair Employment Practices Commission budget estimates.
  - 0169. Fair Employment Practices Commission (June 16-30, 1942). 149 pages., 2 (Reel 20)
    Major Topics: Summary and findings of Fair Employment Practices Commission hearings on Negro discrimination cases in the South; minutes and report of the Negro National Defense Committee; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; United States Employment Service discontinuance of separate employment offices for whites and Negroes; Titeflex Metal Hose Company case; defense training courses for Negroes.
  - 0318. Fair Employment Practices Commission (July 1942). 237 pages., 3 (Reel 20)
    Major Topics: Minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; United States Employment Service discrimination policy; occupational deferment under the Selective Service System; list of government-owned, privately operated ordnance plants; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; list of Fair Employment Practices Commission members; summary of compliance with Fair Employment Practices Commission findings by firms in the Chicago area; summary and findings of Fair Employment Practices Commission hearings on Negro discrimination cases in the South, Fair Employment Practices Commission clipping digest; proposed congressional act to prohibit employment discrimination; Fair Employment Practices Commission reorganization; employment of Negroes by the United States Civil Service Commission.
  - 0555. Fair Employment Practices Commission (August 1942). 199 pages., 4 (Reel 20)
    Major Topics: Emancipation Day celebrations in Canada; Fair Employment Practices Commission relationship with War Manpower Commission; Fair Employment Practices Commission findings in the Titeflex Metal Hose Company case; Fair Employment Practices Commission functions and jurisdictions; report on Hispanics in the war effort; racial discriminations in the South; United States Employment Service discrimination policy; discriminatory practices of railroad companies against Negro labor; report on national defense migration; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; progress report of the Bay Area Council Against Discrimination.
  - 0754. Fair Employment Practices Commission (September 1942). 143 pages., 5 (Reel 20)
    Major Topics: Discrimination against Negroes by railroad companies and unions; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; materials in the National Archives relating to labor and labor problems; seniority of white and colored trainmen; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meeting.
  - 0897. Fair Employment Practices Commission (October 1942). 183 pages., 6 (Reel 20)
    Major Topics: Relationship between the Fair Employment Practices Commission and the War Manpower Commission; discrimination against Negroes in the railroad industry; list of labor organizations having constitutional provisions disqualifying Negroes from membership; Fair Employment Practices Commission budget estimates; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meeting; summary and findings in Fair Employment Practices Commission cases.
- Fair Employment Practices Commission Files 1942-1943 (Reel 21)
  - 0001. Fair Employment Practices Commission (November 1942). 225 pages., 1 (Reel 21)
    Major Topics: Complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; Fair Employment Practices Commission reorganization; discrimination against Negroes in the railroad industry; antidiscrimination clauses in defense contracts; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; Capital Transit Company case; Kilgore report; Fair Employment Practices Commission operations bulletin; decisions and proceedings of the National War Labor Board and the National Labor Relations Board; summary and findings in the Fair Employment Practices Commission cases; United States Employment Service operating policy.
  - 0226. Fair Employment Practices Commission (December 1942). 201 pages., 2 (Reel 21)
    Major Topics: Fair Employment Practices Commission progress report; Fair Employment Practices Commission budget; report of the chairman of the War Manpower Commission; discrimination against Negroes by the railroad industry and unions; upgrading and hiring of Negroes as Pullman conductors; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission hearing in the Pittsburgh Plate Glass Company case; samples of firms with fair employment policies.
  - 0427. (1942). 70 pages., 3 (Reel 21)
    Major Topics: Proposed elimination of discriminatory practices by the Civil Service; discrimination against Negroes by the railroad industry; samples of firms with fair employment policies; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; transfer of Fair Employment Practices Commission to the War Manpower Commission.
  - 0497. Fair Employment Practices Commission (1942). 251 pages., 4 (Reel 21)
    Major Topics: Discrimination against Negroes by the railroad industry; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; summary of Fair Employment Practice Commission hearing on discrimination in defense training; report on how management can integrate Negroes in war industries in New York state; special research report on the Negro worker; recommendations to Fair Employment Practices Commission for approval of staff appointments, promotions, and placement; Fair Employment Practices Commission budget estimates.
  - 0748. Fair Employment Practices Commission (January-February 10, 1943)., 5 (Reel 21)
    Major Topics: Minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; adjustment of complaint against the War Shipping Administration; discrimination against Negroes by the railroad industry; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; development of nutrition program for federal workers; Fair Employment Practices Commission reorganization; defense training for Negroes.
- Fair Employment Practices Commission Files 1943 (Reel 22)
  - 0001. Fair Employment Practices Commission (February 11-28, 1943). 284 pages., 1 (Reel 22)
    Major Topics: Complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; Fair Employment Practices Commission operations bulletin; United States military compliance with antidiscrimination executive order; employment and assignment of Negroes in the federal civil service; summary of Fair Employment Practices Commission hearings in the Pittsburgh Plate Glass Company case; Fair Employment Practices Commission budget estimates; proceedings of the Conference on Scope and Powers of Fair Employment Practices Commission; discrimination against Negroes by the railroad industry; Columbia Steel Company case.
  - 0285. Fair Employment Practices Commission (March-April 15, 1943)., 2 (Reel 22)
    Major Topics: Complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government department and agencies; work stoppages due to discrimination against Negroes; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; list of War Manpower Commission personnel; report on action on United States Service 510 reports; Fair Employment Practices Commission reorganization; Fair Employment Practices Commission personnel; participation of Negroes in the National Youth Administration war program; requests for occupational deferments; Fair Employment Practices Commission report on employment discrimination.
  - 0515. Fair Employment Practices Commission (April 16-July 1943)., 3 (Reel 22)
    Major Topics: Minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; Capital Transit Company case; Fair Employment Practices Commission reorganization; report on the segregation of war workers; Fair Employment Practices Commission personnel recommendations; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; report on utilization of nonwhite workers in war production in the Detroit area; report on equal employment opportunity for Negroes in local transportation systems; Fair Employment Practices Commission May 1943 annual report; creation of American Labor Conference on International Affairs; Fair Employment Practices Commission budget estimates; report on racial discrimination in Pacific Coast shipbuilding industry; report on racial discrimination in the mining and oil industries of the Southwest; Milton Webster reappointed to membership in the Fair Employment Practices Commission; American Federation of Labor Committee on Post War Planning and Minority Group Problems; report on racial discrimination in the United States military.
  - 0848. Fair Employment Practices Commission (August-September 10, 1943). 201 pages., 4 (Reel 22)
    Major Topics: Operating agreement between Fair Employment Practices Commission and the War Manpower Commission on nondiscrimination program; proposed establishment of a Fair Employment Practices Commission sub-regional office in Detroit; Fair Employment Practices Commission personnel; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; War Manpower Commission field instructions; cooperative agreement between Fair Employment Practices Commission and the War Labor Board; responsibility of the War Manpower Commission in the utilization of minority groups; Fair Employment Practices Commission budget estimates; discrimination against Negroes by the railroad industry.
- Fair Employment Practices Commission Files 1943 (Reel 23)
  - 0001. Fair Employment Practices Commission (September 11-30, 1943). 336 pages., 1 (Reel 23)
    Major Topics: Discrimination against Negroes by the railroad industry and unions; seniority lists for dining car employees; Fair Employment Practices Commission hearings, findings, and directives on discrimination complaints against the Pennsylvania Railroad Company, the Southern Railway Company, the Louisville and Nashville Railroad, the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad, New York Central Railroad, the Norfolk Southern Railway Company, Chesapeake and Ohio Railway Company, the Jacksonville Terminal Company, the Georgia Railroad, the Gulf, Mobile, and Ohio Railroad, the Norfolk and Western Railway Company, the Central of Georgia Railway Company, the Southeastern Carriers' Conference, the Illinois Central Railroad System, the Union Pacific Railroad, the Chicago and North Western Railway Company, the Atlantic Coast Line Company, the Seaboard Airline Railway Company, the Saint Louis-San Francisco Railway Company, and the Southern Railway Company; National Mediation Board agreement between the Southern Carriers' Conference Committee and the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Engineers; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; description of functions of Fair Employment Practices Commission personnel; Fair Employment Practices Commission rules and regulations; Fair Employment Practices Commission hearings in Dow Chemical Company case.
  - 0337. Fair Employment Practices Commission (October-December 1943). 292 pages., 2 (Reel 23)
    Major Topics: Fair Employment Practices Commission hearings and findings in the Northwest Mining and Exchange Company case and the Philadelphia Transportation Company case; Malcolm Ross appointed Fair Employment Practices Commission Chairman; minutes of Fair Employment Practices Commission meetings; discrimination against Negroes by the railroad industry; report on the employment of aliens in war industries; sample of cases handled successfully by the Fair Employment Practices Commission; employment relationship to the Committee for Congested Production Areas; complaints regarding discrimination in the national defense program and in federal government departments and agencies; report on developments in the employment of Negroes in war industries; agreement between the National War Labor Board and Fair Employment Practices Commission; list of officers of the local divisions of the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Fair Employment Practices Commission budget; discrimination in federal housing for war workers; Capital Transit Company case; Oregon Shipbuilding Corporation case.